Finding Aid for the Ferdinand Praeger Collection of Scores, circa 1829-1891
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Keyboard works, 1837-1891, I.; Item 001-369
  - Piano, 1837-1891, A.; Item 001-332
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Liebes Bothschaft [i.e. Botschaft?] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Liebes Botschaft (Box 4, Item 198)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Lullaby, piano, no. 1 Lullaby = Schlummerlied, no. 1: piano / [18--], [5] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Schlummerlied (Box 4, Item 199)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [4].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Maestosos, piano, D major Maestoso [in D major] / [18--], [5] p. of ms. music; 29 cm. (Box 4, Item 200)
      For piano. Title from initial tempo-expression marking. Holograph (Ink).
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Marches, piano, A♭ major Marche / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 201)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Marches, piano, D major Marcia; Bolero / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 4, Item 202)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Marcia numbered 5, Bolero numbered 6.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Mater dolorosa Mater dolorosa, or Holy hour: Adagio religioso [for] piano / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Mater dolorosa Alternate title: Holy hour Alternate title: Adagio religioso (Box 4, Item 203)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Matrosafest / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 4, Item 204)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Mazurkas, piano, A minor Mazurka [in A minor] / 1889, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 205)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 8 Nov. 89.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Mazurkas, piano, B♭ major Mazurka [in B flat major] / 1838, [2] p. of ms. music; 30 cm. (Box 4, Item 206)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 23 Septbr 1838; p. [1] margin: London, Sunday morning 23rd Sept. 1838.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Mazurkas, piano, F major Mazurka [in F major] pour piano / [183-?], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 207)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Insert consisting of top half of page pasted on p. [1].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Mazurkas, piano. Selections [Three mazurkas] / 1888, [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 208)
      For piano. Title supplied by cataloger. Holograph (Ink). Caption and colophon: 25 Aug 88.
      Contents: [No. 1. E♭ major] -- No. 2. [A minor] -- No. 3. [C major].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Meditation, piano, A♭ major Meditation [in A flat major] / 1889, [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 209)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: Nov. 89. Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [2-3].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Meditation, piano, C major Meditation [in C major] / 1890, [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 210)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 18/1 90.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Meditation, piano, F major (Andantino) Meditation for the piano / [18--], 5 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 211)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Initial tempo-expression marking: Andantino. Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 1, 4.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Meditation, piano, F major (Ben moderato) Meditation [in F major] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 212)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Initial tempo-expression marking: Ben moderato.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Mephisto / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 213)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Minuets, piano, C major Minuetto / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 30 cm. (Box 4, Item 214)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Minuets, piano, G major Minuet / 1890, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 215)
      For piano. Caption title. Manuscript (Ink). "Composed & dedicated to the Rev'd F.C. Blyth by F. Praeger. 21-1-90"--Caption. "E.B. 4.2.'90"--p. [2].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Moderatos, piano, A♭ major Moderato [in A flat major] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 216)
      For piano. Title from initial tempo marking. Holograph (Ink), with additional markings in pencil. Corrections on insert pasted on p. [2].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Moderatos, piano, E♭ major Moderato [in E flat major] / [18--], 11 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 217)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Moderatos, piano, G major Moderato [in G major] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 218)
      For piano. Title from initial tempo marking. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [2]. Three systems of sketches follow the end of the piece on p. [4].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Moderato assai [in B flat major] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 219)
      For piano. Title from initial tempo-expression marking. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Molto moderato [in A minor] / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 4, Item 220)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Monaco: morceau de genre / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 4, Item 221)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 A moorish melody = melodie moresque / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Melodie moresque (Box 4, Item 222)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Morceaux caracteristiques Six morceaux caracteristiques: pour piano / [18--], [12] p. of ms. music; 32 cm.; Alternate title: Morceaux caracteristiques Removed to separate box due to high level of mold. (Box 17, Item 223)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
      Contents: No. 1, Fatima -- No. 2, Sweet sorrow -- No. 3, [untitled] -- No. 4, Barcarolle -- No. 5, Soldier's farewell -- No. 6, [untitled].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 1 Nocturne for piano no.1 / 1875, [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 224)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). "Composed and dedicated to his friend L.B. Mosely [i.e. B.L. Mosely?]"--Caption. Caption: Xmas day 1875. Corrections on insert pasted on p. [4]. Label inserted: 14 (17 crossed out) Nocturnes.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 5 Nocturne [for] piano no.5 [in] G / [between 1875 and 1889], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 225)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 6 Nocturne no.6 / 1881, [3] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 226)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: July 1881.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 7 Nocturne no. 7 / [between 1875 and 1889], 4 p. of ms. music; 28 cm. (Box 5, Item 227)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 8 Nocturne no. 8 / [between 1875 and 1889], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 228)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 9 Nocturne no. 9 / [between 1875 and 1889], 2 p. of ms. music; 33 cm. (Box 5, Item 229)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1]-2.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 10 Nocturne no. 10 / [between 1875 and 1889], 3 p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 230)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 11 Nocturne no. 11 / [between 1875 and 1889], [4] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 231)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1, 2, 4].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 12 Nocturne no. 12 / [between 1875 and 1889], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 232)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 13 Nocturne no. 13 / [between 1875 and 1889], [3] p. of ms. music; 30 cm. (Box 5, Item 233)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [3].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 14 Nocturne no. 14 / [between 1875 and 1889], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 234)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 15 Nocturne pour piano no. 15 / [between 1875 and 1889], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 235)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 16 Nocturne no. 16 / [between 1875 and 1889], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 236)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, no. 17 Auf dem Wasser =On the water: nocturne no. 17 / [between 1875 and 1889], [4] p. of ms. music; 35 cm.; Alternate title: On the water Alternate title: Nocturne no. 17 (Box 5, Item 237)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, A♭ major Nocturne [in A flat major] / [between 1875 and 1889], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 238)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, B♭ major Nocturne [in B flat major] / [between 1875 and 1889], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 239)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, E♭ major (1888 Aug. 23) Nocturne [in E flat major], 1888, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 240)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 23 August 88.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, E♭ major (1888 Sept. 18) Nocturne [in E flat major], 1888, [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 241)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 17 Sept. 1888; Colophon: 18 Sept. 1888.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, E♭ major (Moderato) Nocturne [in E flat major, Moderato] / [between 1875 and 1889], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 242)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, E♭ major (Molto moderato) Nocturne [in E flat major, Molto moderato] / [between 1875 and 1889], [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 243)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Initial tempo marking: Molto moderato.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Nocturnes, piano, F major Nocturne [in F major] / 1889, 4 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 244)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 8 May 89; p. 3 margin: 11 May 89; p. 4 margin: June 30th, 1889.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 La petite fadette: pour piano / [18--], [5] p. of ms. music; 24 x 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 245)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Polka, piano Polka / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 246)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Polka-mazurka / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 247)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Popular ballad / 1889, [1] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 248)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 13 May 89.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Preludes, piano, no. 1 Präludium no. 1 / [between 1880 and 1882], [2] p. of ms. music; 28 cm. (Box 5, Item 249)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Label inserted: 8 Präludien von Ferdinand Praeger.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Preludes, piano, no. 2 Präludium no. 2 / [between 1880 and 1882], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 250)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Preludes, piano, no. 3 Präludium no. 3 / [between 1880 and 1882], [1] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 251)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Preludes, piano, no. 4 Präludium no. 4 / [between 1880 and 1882], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 252)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Preludes, piano, no. 5 Präludium no. 5 / 1880, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 253)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 12/12 1880.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Preludes, piano, no. 6 Präludium no. 6 / 1882, [3] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 254)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1]. Caption: 21/12 1882.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Preludes, piano, no. 7 Präludium no. 7 / 1882, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 255)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 26/12 1882.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Preludes, piano, no. 8 Präludium no. 8 / 1882, [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 256)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [1]. Caption: 30/12 1882.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Presto agitato: C minor / 1890, [5] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 257)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 90.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Redowa / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 258)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Rhapsodies, piano, no. 1 Rhapsodie no. 1 :Mephisto / [18--], [4] p. of ms. music; 35 cm.; Alternate title: Mephisto (Box 5, Item 259)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Rhapsodies, piano, no. 2 Rhapsodie pour piano, no. 2 / [18--], 6 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 260)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. 3.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Romances, piano, no. 16 Romance no. 16 :Fatima / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Fatima (Box 5, Item 261)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Romances, piano, A♭ major Romanze fürs clavier [in A flat major] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 29 cm. (Box 5, Item 262)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Paper torn, small amount of content missing.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Romances, piano, A♭ major (1844) Romanza [in A flat major] / 1844, [4] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 263)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [2-4]. Caption: 1844.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Romances, piano, G major Romanza [in G major] / 1847, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 264)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1-2]. Caption: 1847.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Romanza di gondoliera :transcription Otello / [18--], 5 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 265)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1]-3.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Romances, piano, E♭ major Romance for piano [in E flat major] / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 266)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Russian airs / [18--], [1] p. of ms. music; 24 x 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 267)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Unidentified sketches on verso: Moderato and Lento.
      Contents: [No. I. A minor] -- No. II. [C major] -- No. III. [A minor].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, A♭ major Scherzo [in A flat major] / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 268)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, C major (1888 Dec.) Scherzo [in C major], 1888, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 269)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 18.12.88; Colophon: 30/12.88.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, C major (1890 Dec.) Scherzo [in C major], 1890, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 270)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 30/11.90; p. [3]: 2/12.90.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, E♭ major Scherzo [in E flat major :incomplete / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 271)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Incomplete work.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, E♭ major (Allegretto) Scherzo [in E flat major :Allegretto] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 272)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Initial tempo marking: Allegretto.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, E♭ major (Vivace) Scherzo [in E flat major :Vivace] / [18--], 3 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 273)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Initial tempo marking: Vivace.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, F major Scherzo [in F major] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 274)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Correction on insert pasted on p. [2].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, G major, (1887) Scherzo [in G major], 1887, 3 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 275)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). At end of score, partially effaced: 1887.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, G major (1888 June) Scherzo in G / 1888, [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 276)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Cover: June 10th 88; Caption: 18 May 88. Corrections on insert pasted on p. [2].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, G major, (1890 Dec.) Scherzo [in G major], 1890, 4 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 277)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: 2/12.90.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, G major (Allegretto) Scherzo [in G major :Allegretto] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 278)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Initial tempo marking: Allegretto. Corrections on inserts pasted on p. [1].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, G major (Allegro vivace) Scherzo [in G major :Allegro vivace] / [18--], [9] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 279)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Initial tempo marking: Allegro vivace. Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzos, piano, G major (Moderato) Scherzo [in G major :Moderato] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 280)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Scherzo allegretto, piano, E♭ major Scherzo allegretto / [18--], [3] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 281)
      For piano. Caption title. Additional title in caption indecipherable. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 1-3. Paper of p. [1]-2 has hole in it and is missing small quantity of notes.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Serenades, piano, E major Serenade [in E major] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 5, Item 282)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Serenades, piano, F major Serenade [in F major] / [18--], [2] p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 5, Item 283)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 1, C minor 1st sonata in C minor / 1890, 20 p. of ms. music; 33 cm.; Alternate title: First sonata in C minor Alternate title: Sonate no. 1 (Box 6, Item 284)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink), with additional markings in pencil. Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 12-13. Cover: June 1st, 1890 [may apply to date of copy; copy in Mondenhauer Archives at Northwestern University dated 1864].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 1, C minor 1st grand sonata in C minor / [18--], [33] p. of ms. music; 35 cm.; Alternate title: First grand sonata in C minor (Box 6, Item 285)
      For piano. Cover title. Manuscript (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [18].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 5, A minor 5th sonata for piano / [18--], [24] p. of ms. music; 35 cm.; Alternate title: Fifth sonata for piano (Box 6, Item 286)
      For piano. Cover title. Manuscript (Ink). Corrections on insert pasted on p. [17].
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 6, E♭ major Sixth sonata, or Symphony, or Symphonic poem / [18--], 13 p. of ms. music; 36 cm.; Alternate title: Sixth sonata Alternate title: Sixth symphony Alternate title: Sixth symphonic poem Alternate title: 6th Symphonic poem in E♭, or Sonata Alternate title: VI Sonate (Box 6, Item 287)
      For piano. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 7, D minor Seventh sonata in D minor / [18--], 16 p. of ms. music; 36 cm.; At head of title page: 7th symphonic poem Alternate title: 7th symphonic poem or sonata in D minor (Box 6, Item 288)
      Incomplete: missing pages 11-12.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 9, F major Ninth sonata in F :(symphonic poem) / [18--], 15 p. of ms. music; 37 cm. (Box 6, Item 289)
      For piano. Holograph (Ink). At head of title page: Dedicated to Mrs. Wyatt Smith. Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 11, 13.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 10, F major 10th symphonic poem in F / 1880, 16 p. of ms. music; 36 cm.; Alternate title: Tenth symphonic poem in F Alternate title: Tenth symphonic poem for piano (Box 6, Item 290)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Caption: Aug. 1880. Cataloger's note: Praeger's symphonic poems for piano are numbered within the sequence of his piano sonatas. Sonatas 6 and 7 are titled as both piano sonata and symphonic poem.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 11, F major Eleventh symphonic poem in F / [18--], 24 p. of ms. music; 36 cm.; Additional title on cover: Eleventh poême symphonique (Box 6, Item 291)
      For piano. Title from label on cover. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 8, 16. Cataloger's note: Praeger's symphonic poems for piano are numbered within the sequence of his piano sonatas. Sonatas 6 and 7 are titled as both piano sonata and symphonic poem.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 12, C major Twelfth symphonic poem in C / 1883, 20 p. of ms. music; 37 cm.; Alternate title: 12th symphonic poem (Box 6, Item 292)
      For piano. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. Caption: Good Friday 1883. Cataloger's note: Praeger's symphonic poems for piano are numbered within the sequence of his piano sonatas. Sonatas 6 and 7 are titled as both piano sonata and symphonic poem.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 13, A♭ major 13th sonata / 1884, 13 p. of ms. music; 35 cm.; Alternate title: Thirteenth sonata (Box 6, Item 293)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. Caption of p. 2: 14 Aug 1881, finished 22 August 1884.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 14, D major Fourteenth sonata for piano in D / 1884, [1], 12. p. of ms. music; 36 cm.; Alternate title: 14th sonata (Box 6, Item 294)
      For piano. Cover title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. Cover: 1884. Unnumbered page on cover verso contains a Funeral march in D minor. Entire leaf of p. 10 pasted onto verso of p. 9. There is music visible on the verso of the pasted p. 10.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 15, E minor 15th sonata in E minor / 1885, 17 p. of ms. music; 37 cm. (Box 6, Item 295)
      For piano. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout. Cover: May 1885.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 16, C minor Sixteenth sonata for piano in C minor / [18--], 15 p. of ms. music; 35 cm. (Box 6, Item 296)
      For piano. Cover title Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted throughout.
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 18, C minor Sonata no. 18 / [18--], 12 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 6, Item 297)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 19, G minor Sonata no. 19 / [18--], 12 p. of ms. music; 31 cm. (Box 6, Item 298)
    - Praeger, Ferdinand, 1815-1891 Sonatas, piano, no. 20, C minor 20th sonata in C minor / 1887, 12 p. of ms. music; 31 cm.; Alternate title: Twentieth sonata (Box 6, Item 299)
      For piano. Caption title. Holograph (Ink). Corrections on inserts pasted on p. 1, 5. Caption: 21 June 1887; Caption on p. 7: 27 June 1887.